National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records1972-2006, Undated 1981-2006
nam_apap298
27.55 cubic ft.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Since 1976 the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty has been working to educate the public about the failings and inconsistencies of capital punishment in the United States. Founded after the Gregg v. Georgia Supreme Court decision in 1976, the NCADP has emerged as one of the more influential national anti-death penalty organizations. The collection contains the group’s internal case files, administrative material, publications, petitions, photographic materials, video tapes, and audio cassettes.
National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (U.S.)
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
The National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty donated all items in this collection to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2007.
Administrative History
The National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP) is the largest national organization exclusively devoted to abolishing the death penalty. The NCADP provides information, advocates for public policy, and mobilizes and supports individuals and institutions which reject the use of capital punishment. Through these methods the NCADP hopes to eliminate the death penalty in the United States and supports efforts to abolish the death penalty worldwide.
The NCADP was founded in 1976 following the Gregg v. Georgia Supreme Court decision, which reinstated the death penalty in the United States. Two American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) staff members, Deborah Leavy and Henry Schwarzchild, gathered a group of anti-capital punishment advocates one week after the Gregg decision. The organization that resulted brought together 26 affiliate organizations to coordinate their actions at the national level. The NCADP began its life housed within the ACLU offices in New York. Shortly after 1982 the group relocated to Philadelphia and, in 1987, moved to its current location in Washington D.C.
As a Washington based advocacy group, the NCADP lobbies against capital punishment through a variety of methods that include organizing protests and increasing public awareness. The NCADP uses a number of non-violent methods to draw attention to, and advance, their campaign at local, state and national levels.
Since its inception, the NCADP has been working to educate and inform the public about the failings and inconsistencies of the death penalty. The NCADP’s campaign against capital punishment hinges on four core areas of advocacy: legislative, media, grassroots, and human rights. These efforts are accomplished through an annual conference, distribution of national publications such as LifeLines, the newsletter of the NCADP, and the National Execution Alert Network, a system which provides updates on pending executions. Founded in 1984, the Alert Network is a tracking and warning project keyed to executions – directing when and what actions should be taken in protest. Since 1981, the NCADP has hosted an annual conference which brings abolitionists from across the country together to analyze the past years successes and shortcomings and to strategize the goals and objectives for the coming year. Additionally, the NCADP compiles statistics and publishes findings on a variety of subjects concerning the death penalty including The Abolitionist Directory, a national listing of every organization and individual working against capital punishment and The Death Penalty Exchange, a handbook for organizers.
The NCADP has achieved recent victories in its struggle to end capital punishment. Through the efforts of its Stop Killing Kids Campaign, an initiative that sought to bring an end to the death penalty for offenders whose crimes were committed while they were under the age of 18, NCADP was successful in ending the death penalty as punishment for juveniles in several states. In 2006 NCADP successfully fought death penalty reinstatement efforts in Wisconsin, and the group has played a significant role in winning clemency for several death row inmates.
The National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records documents the administration, avocation, and lobbying activities of the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty from 1976 to 2001.
The largest portion of the collection contains the NCADP’s internal case files. These are divided into Adult, Juvenile, and Innocence sub series comprised of folders which represent an individual capital case. Each file contains trial proceedings, news clippings, artwork, death warrants, and correspondence between the NCADP and death row inmates, government officials, and various affiliate organizations.
The NCADP Records also contain the group’s publications, materials gathered from conferences, photographs, audio and video material, and signed petitions from the Stop Killing Kids campaign against the death penalty for juveniles.
The Subject Files series contains research material related to the various aspects of the death penalty but with a focus on education. Folders include material on death penalty law in the United States and abroad. Folders in this series contain articles, correspondence, news clippings, photographs, press releases, statements, and reports. Topics covered include advocacy, discrimination, families, juveniles, medical issues, and other aspects of death penalty law. This series also includes material from several affiliate organizations.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Case Files, 1988-2006, Undated
Subseries 1.1: Adults, 1988-2006, Undated
Subseries 1.2: Juveniles, 1994-2002, Undated
Subseries 1.3: Innocence, 1998-2000, Undated
Series 2 - Publications, 1982-2004, Undated
Series 3 - Subject Files, 1972-2005, Undated
Series 4 - Conferences, 1981-2005, Undated
Series 5 - Petitions, 1999
Series 6 - Photographs, 1976-2001, Undated
Series 7 - Audio, 1981-2005, Undated
Series 8 - Video, 1985-2005
This collection is grouped in to eight file series, the largest of which is the Case File which consists of the Adults, Juveniles, and Innocence subseries.
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (U.S.); Capital punishment--Political aspects--United States; Capital punishment--Social aspects--United States; Capital punishment--United States; Capital punishment--United States--Cases; Political activists--20th century; Political activists--Legal status, laws, etc.; Political activists--United States; Case files; Correspondence; Criminal court records; Ephemera (general); Fliers (printed matter); Legal documents; Newspapers; Petitions
Container List
- Case Files, 1988-2006, Undated; nam_apap298-1; 12.55 cubic ft.
  Arrangement:
  Split into three subseries, Adults, Juveniles, and Innocence cases, and ordered alphabetically
  Contents:
  The NCADP collection is comprised mainly of case files. Files include newspaper clippings, publicity materials, and correspondence between the NCADP, inmates, lawyers, and family and friends. Some artwork, court transcripts, and death warrants are also present. Each folder represents a death penalty case that the organization was interested in or involved with.
  - Adults, 1988-2006, Undated; nam_apap298-1.1; 9 cubic ft.
    Alphabetical by last name
    Death row inmates over the age of 17
    - Abrecht, Alfred (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adanandus, Dwight (TX), 1997; nam_apap298-1.1_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adcox, Keith (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adkins, Ricky (AL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ainsworth, Steven (CA), 1991; nam_apap298-1.1_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Akers, Thomas (VA), 2001; nam_apap298-1.1_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Alcala, Rodney (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Aldrich, Donald (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Aldridge, Rulford (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Alexander, Andre (CA), 1996; nam_apap298-1.1_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Alexander, Caruthers (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Alfaro, Maria (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Allen, Gary (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Allen, Robert (DE), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Allen, Wanda (OK), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allison, Watson (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Allridge, James (TX), 1993; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Alston, Charlie (NC), 2001; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Alvarez, Manuel Machado (CA), 1992; nam_apap298-1.1_19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Alvord, Gary E. (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Amaya-Ruiz, Jose (AZ), 2000; 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_21 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Amos, Bernard (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_22 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Anderson, Michael (NE), 1995; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Anderson, Stephen (CA), 2001; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_24 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Andrews, Jesse (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_25 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Apanovitch, Anthony (OH), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_26 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Apelt, Michael and Rudi (AZ), 1993; 1998; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_27 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Appel, Martin (PA), 1994; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Aranda, Arturo (TX), 1990; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_29 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Arias, Pedro (CA), 1996; nam_apap298-1.1_30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Armstrong, Lancelot (FL), 1991; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_31 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Arnold, Jermarr (TX), 1991; 1994; 2001; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_32 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Arnold, John D. (SC), 1998; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_33 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Arther, Limmie (SC), 1988; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_34 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Arther, Thomas (AL), 1991; nam_apap298-1.1_35 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Atkins, Daryl (VA), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_36 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Atwood, Frank Jarvis (AZ), 1991; nam_apap298-1.1_37 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Atworth, Robert (TX), 1999; nam_apap298-1.1_38 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Avila, Johnny (CA), 1994; nam_apap298-1.1_39 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Azania, Zulo A. (IN), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_40 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Babbit, Mannuel (CA), 1998; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_41 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Bacigalupo, Miguel (CA), 1992; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Bacon, Robert (NC), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_43 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Baez, Orlando (PA), 1993; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_44 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bailey, Billy, (DE) Executed January 25, 1996, Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_45 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Baird, Arthur (IN), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_46 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Baker, Wesley (MD), 2002; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_47 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Baldree, Ernest (TX), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_48 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Baldwin, Brian (AL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_49 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Balfour, Susie (MS), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_50 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Banda, Esequel (TX), Executed December 11, 1995, Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_51 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Banks Jr., Delma (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_52 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Bannister A.J (MO), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_53 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Barber, Danny (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_54 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Barbour, Christopher (AL), 2001; nam_apap298-1.1_55 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Barefield, John (TX), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_56 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Barnabei, Derek (VA), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_57 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Barnes, Odell (TX), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_58 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Barnes, Willis (TX), 1999; nam_apap298-1.1_59 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Basemore, William (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_60 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Bassette, Herbert (VA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_61 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Bates, Kayle B. (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_62 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Bates, Wayne (TN), 1994; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_63 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Battle, Thomas (MO), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_64 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Baze, Ralph Jr. (KY), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_65 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Bean, Anthony (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_66 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Beardslee, Donald (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_67 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Beasley, Leslie (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_68 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Beathard, James (TX) [1 of 2], Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_69 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Beathard, James (TX) [2 of 2], 1999; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_70 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Beaty, Donald (AZ), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_71 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Beauer, Gregory (VA), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_72 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Beauers, Thomas (VA), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_73 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Beets, Betty Lou (TX), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_74 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Behringer, Earl "Duke" (TX) Executed June 11, 1997, Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_75 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Bell, Larry (FL), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_76 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Bell, Randy (AL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_77 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Bell, Steven (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_78 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Bell, Walter (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_79 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Bell, William H. (SC), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_80 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Belmontes, Fernando (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_81 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Bemore, Terry (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_82 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Beltron, Noe (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_83 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Belyeu, Clifton (TX), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_84 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Benavides, Vincente (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_85 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Benefiel, Bill (IN), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_86 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Benn, Gary (WA), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_87 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Bennett, Eric Wayne (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_88 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Bennett, Ronald (VA), 1996; nam_apap298-1.1_89 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Berget, Roger (OK), 2000; nam_apap298-1.1_90 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Berry, Earl W. (MS), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_91 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Berry, Wilford Lee (OH), 1997; 2005; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_92 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Berryman, Rodney (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_93 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Besaraba, Joseph (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_94 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Bey, Eric D. Clemmons (MO), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_95 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Bies, Michael (OH), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_96 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Bigby, James (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_97 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Billiot, James, (MS), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_98 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Birdsong, Ralph "Hakim" (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_99 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Bittaker, Lawrence (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_100 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Bivins, Gernald (IN) [1 of 2], Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_101 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Bivins, Gernald (IN) [2 of 2], 2001; nam_apap298-1.1_102 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Bjorklund, Roger (NE), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_103 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Black, Gary W. (MO), 2001; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_104 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Blackmon, Ricky (TX), 1999; nam_apap298-1.1_105 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Blair, Michael (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_106 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Bland, Warren J. (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_107 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Blackenship, Roy (GA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_108 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Bloom, Robert (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_109 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Blystone, Scott (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_110 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Boggess, Clifford (TX), 1998; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_111 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Bolden, Clifford (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_112 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Bolick, Jr., William (MO), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_113 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Bolin, Oscar Ray (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_114 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Bolin, Paul (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_115 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Bond, Jesse (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_116 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Bonilla, Stephen (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_117 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Booker, Stephen (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_118 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Booth, John (MD), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_119 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Bottoson, Linroy (FL), 2002; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_120 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Bower, Lester (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_121 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Bowling, Thomas (KY), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_122 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Boyd, Arthur M. (NC), 1999; nam_apap298-1.1_123 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Boyd, Ronald (OK), 1999; nam_apap298-1.1_124 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - Boyd, Russell Ernest (IN) and Gosch, Lesley (TX), 1993; nam_apap298-1.1_125 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - Boyd, Richard (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_126 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - Boyle, Daniel L. (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_127 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - Box, Christopher (CA), 1991; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_128 (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Bracy, Edward (PA), 1995; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_129 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - Bracey, William (AZ), 1991; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_130 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - Bradford, Bill (CA), 1998; nam_apap298-1.1_131 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Bradford,Gayland (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_132 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Bradford, Mark (CA), 1990; 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_133 (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - Bradley, Danny (AL), 2001; nam_apap298-1.1_134 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - Branch, Erik S. (FL), 1994; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_135 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Breard, Angel Francisco (VA), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_136 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Breedlove, McArthur (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_137 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Brewer, John (AZ), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_138 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Brimage, Richard, Jr. (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_139 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bronshtein, Antuan (PA), 1999; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_140 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Brooks, Billy (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_141 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Broussard, Windell (TX), 2001; nam_apap298-1.1_142 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Brown, Albert Greenwood, Jr. (CA), 1993; nam_apap298-1.1_143 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Arthur Jr. (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_144 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Charles (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_145 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Brown, David (NC), 1998; nam_apap298-1.1_146 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Brown, David J. (OK), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_147 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Brown, Deborah (IN), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_148 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Brown, Gary (AL), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_149 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Brown, James (GA), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_150 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Brown, John (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_151 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Brown, John (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_152 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Brown, Raymond E. (AL), 1991; nam_apap298-1.1_153 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Brown, Vernon (MO), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_154 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Broxton, Eugene Alvin (TX), 1994; nam_apap298-1.1_155 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bruce, Kenneth (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_156 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bryan, Anthony B. (FL), 1999; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_157 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Bryan, Robert L. (OK), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_158 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bryson, William (OK), 2000; nam_apap298-1.1_159 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Buchanan, Doug (VA), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_160 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Buenoano, Judi (FL), 1998; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_161 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Buenrostro, Dora (CA), 1998; nam_apap298-1.1_162 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Buhl, Kevin Lee (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_163 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Burdine, Calvin (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_164 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Burks, John (TX), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_165 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Burns, William (TX), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_166 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Burris, Gary (IN), 1997; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_167 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Burton, Andre (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_168 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bush, John (FL), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_169 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Bussell, Charles W. (KY), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_170 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Butler, Raymond (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_171 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Butler, Sabrina (MS), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_172 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Butler, Steven (TX), 2000; nam_apap298-1.1_173 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Buttrum, Janice (GA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_174 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Byrd, John (OH), 1994; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_175 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Burdine, Calvin (TX), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_176 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Cade, Calvin (AL), 1993; nam_apap298-1.1_177 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Cain, Burl (LA), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_178 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Cain, James (SC), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_179 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Calambro, Alvaro (NV), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_180 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Calderon, Arthur (CA), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_181 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Caldwell, Jeffrey (TX), 1991; nam_apap298-1.1_182 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Callins, Bruce (TX), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_183 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Camacho, Genaro R. (TX), 1990; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_184 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Campbell, Charles (WA), 2002; nam_apap298-1.1_185 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Campbell, James (FL), 1996; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_186 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Campbell, Ken (TN), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_187 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Cannon, Joseph (TX), Executed April 22, 1998, Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_188 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Cantu Jr., Domingo (TX), 1999; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_189 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Cantu, Peter (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_190 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Cardona, Ana (FL), 1992; nam_apap298-1.1_191 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Cargill, David L. (GA), 1998; nam_apap298-1.1_192 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Caro, Fernando (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_193 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Carpenter, David (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_194 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Carpenter, David (FL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_195 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Carpenter, James (PA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_196 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Carr, Darell Colenn (TX), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_197 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Carriger, Paris (AZ), 1995; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_198 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Carrington, Celeste (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_199 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Carroll, Robert (AL), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_200 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Carter, Dean (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_201 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Carter, Marcus (NC), 2000; nam_apap298-1.1_202 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Carter, Robert (TX) [1 of 2], 1998; 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_203 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Carter, Robert (TX) [2 of 2], Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_204 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Carter, Tracy (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_205 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Cartwright, Richard (TX), 2005; nam_apap298-1.1_206 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Caruthers, Alexander (TX), 2000; nam_apap298-1.1_207 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Cash, Randall Scott (CA), Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_208 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Castro, Edward (FL), 2000; Undated; nam_apap298-1.1_209 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Castro, John (OK), 1992; nam_apap298-1.1_210 (Box 2, Folder 76)